# Ryan Stutesman (they/them)

Engineering leader with a breadth of experience in full-stack mobile and web development, an impressive ability to communicate and work with a variety of audiences, and a track record of building and maintaining high-performing teams.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **GameChanger** — *Sr. Engineering Manager*

2021 - Now

- Managed a variety of teams and sub-teams, getting exposure to everything from video streaming to overall system architecture.
- Worked with my team and platform teams to improve our video and highlight clipping architecture to support 5x scale.
- Advocated for and owned a project that increased user engagement with highlight clips by 11x and increased subscriptions coming from these clips by 3x.
- Worked closely with a dedicated Product Manager and Product Designer to run projects week-to-week and plan out quarterly and yearly roadmaps.
- Ran a cross-company team responsible for shutting down our legacy app and infrastructure and migrating users, subscriptions, and data to our new app.
- Promoted a senior engineer to manager, continued managing and coaching them, and oversaw their team.
- Took over a struggling team and turned them around to be high-functioning and impactful.
- Lead efforts to improve our technical interview and technical onboarding processes to support our rapid hiring efforts.

# **Wyzant** — Various Roles

2016 - 2021

#### **Engineering Manager**

- Foster learning and development of direct reports by holding effective 1-on-1s, finding or creating growth opportunities, and performing bi-yearly 360 reviews.
- Work with product and marketing to scope and prioritize a variety of projects.
- Cultivate an environment of open & honest communication and feedback to ensure peers and employees could learn and grow.
- Ran several impactful A/B tests and improved A/B testing tools.

## iOS/Full-stack Web Engineer

- Lead engineer for "Ask and Expert" product; an ask-a-tutor forum where tutors could answer students' questions via a text response or a video recording.
- Designed and built an ETL used to select which SEO landing pages to activate to reduce duplicate content issues and improve our SEO rankings.
- Rebuild legacy tutor search API in Go+Elasticsearch, improving search accuracy and conversion rates.

## ÄKTA — iOS Consultant

2016

• Team lead for the UI of the BMW ConnectedDrive app. Worked closely with BMW's in-house developers and stakeholders in an agile environment.

## **Xamarin** — Developer Evangelist

2015 - 2016

• Evangelize the Xamarin and associated products by participating in various speaking engagements, publishing tech blog content, creating demo apps, etc.

# West Monroe Partners — Mobile Consultant

2014 - 2015

• Work with a variety of clients to develop and maintain iOS and Android applications in both Objective-C with Xcode and C# with Xamarin.

#### ryanstutes.com

ryanmstutes@gmail.com 219.613.3829 Based in Chicago

#### **TECH**

Typescript/Node.js, Ruby/Rails, Golang

AWS, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes, MySQL, Postgres, ElasticSearch

System Architecture, Scaling, Resiliency

iOS, Swift, Objective-C Android, Kotlin

HTML/CSS, JS & jQuery, Vue.js

CI/CD, Github, GitLab

## **STRENGTHS**

Communication, leadership, teamwork, agile, prioritization

Creative thinking, problem solving, public speaking

Passion for people, products, and planning/organization

#### **EDUCATION**

**Purdue University** 

Organizational Leadership & Supervision, B.S.

Minors: CS, Communications